# **Rehan Sayyed**

Software Engineer

Well-qualified **MERN Stack Developer** familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2 years of related experience.



## **Contact**

#### Address

Ahmednagar, MH 414001

#### Phone

+91-8888106722

#### F-mail

rehansayyed1216@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rehan-sayyed-0682b220a



# **Education**

2019-08 - 2022-05

## B.Tech: Production Engineering

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology - Pune CGPA: 9.05



## Languages

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Pvthon
- Java



#### **Skills**

MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React,Node)

HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Redux

Nest JS

SQL Material UI

Data Structure and Algorithm (DSA)



## **Tools**

- Git and GitHub
- Postman
- Figma



## **Work History**

2022-09 -2023-11

## **Software Engineer**

LTIMindtree, Pune

- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded <u>performance</u> expectations.
- Delivered completed products within project deadline.
- Integrated <u>third-party tools</u> and components into applications. Prioritized tasks and completed in order of importance.
- Gained knowledge and utilized Redux, Nest JS, and Figma in web app.
- Wrote production-ready code with fluency in modern <u>front-end</u> and <u>back-end</u> <u>frameworks</u>.

2022-03 -2022-06

# **Full Stack Developer Intern**

Mindtree, Remote

- <u>Developed chatbot</u> using Google's NLU platform, <u>DialogFlow</u>, to facilitate user interactions within <u>e-commerce application</u>.
- Created <u>Node.js server</u> to manage communication between the chatbot and the application, ensuring seamless <u>user request processing</u> and integration.
- Enhanced chatbot functionality with <u>webhook</u> integration, enabling real-time communication and <u>dynamic responses</u> between DialogFlow and external services.



### **E-Commerce Application**

Live Demo - <a href="https://aura-a29l.onrender.com/">https://aura-a29l.onrender.com/</a>

Source Code - <a href="https://github.com/Sayyed-rehan/E-commerce-Aura">https://github.com/Sayyed-rehan/E-commerce-Aura</a>

- Developed full stack application using <u>React</u>, MongoDB, <u>Nest.JS</u>, <u>Redux</u> and <u>Figma</u>.
- Designed and implemented user-friendly interface that allows customers to sign in, log out, filter products, add to cart, and rate products
- Integrated Authentication, Authorization, back-end functionality to enable users to manage their shipment addresses, <u>order history</u>, and <u>cancel orders</u>
- Demonstrated ability to deliver secure, <u>scalable</u>, and <u>high-performance</u> web applications that meet customer needs.
- Web app deployment on On render and MongoDB Atlas cloud service

## **Social Media Application**

Live Demo: <a href="https://social-media-uaw8.onrender.com/">https://social-media-uaw8.onrender.com/</a>
Source Code - <a href="https://github.com/Sayyed-rehan/Social-media1">https://github.com/Sayyed-rehan/Social-media1</a>

- Developed MERN stack website with features such as sign-in, login, logout, <u>post</u> <u>creation</u>, <u>deletion</u>, <u>update</u>, and <u>search</u>.
- Implemented user authentication and authorization and <u>bcrypt.js</u> to securely store and verify user credentials in MongoDB.
- Applied Mongoose to create schemas and models for the MongoDB database and perform CRUD operations.
- Web app deployment on On render and MongoDB Atlas cloud service



# **Certifications**

2024-11	Data Structure and Algorithm, Scaler
2023-10	Certified React Advanced, Coursera
2023-10	Developing Back-End Apps with Node.js and Express, Coursera
2023-09	Certified React Basics Coursera